Finding aid for the Bonnie Cashin Collection of Fashion, Theater, and Film Costume Design LSC.0440
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bonnie Cashin collection of fashion, theater, and film costume design
1913-2000
UCLA Library Special Collections
Cashin, Bonnie
LSC.0440
160.0 linear feet (318 boxes and 4 garment racks)
The collection contains Bonnie Cashin's personal archive documenting her design career. The collection includes Cashin's design illustrations, writings on design, contractual paperwork, photographs of her clothing designs, and press materials including press releases and editorial coverage of her work. Personal photographs and letters to Cashin are also included.
Restrictions on Access
Portions of collection unprocessed. Audiovisual and audio materials are unavailable for access. Please contact Special Collections reference (spec-coll@library.ucla.edu) for more information.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL AND AUDIO MATERIALS: Materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Bonnie Cashin estate, July 2003.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9953992523606533
Biography
Bonnie Cashin was born circa September 28, 1908 in Fresno, Calif. In her teens she worked as a fashion illustrator and dance costume designer for Los Angeles dance troupe, Fanchon and Marco. She briefly studied drawing at the Chouinard School of Art in Los Angeles. In 1933 she moved to New York to design costumes for the Roxyette danceline at the Roxy Theater. In 1933, and again in 1935, Cashin studied drawing at the Art Students' League. From 1937 until 1942, she designed for the coat and suit manufacturer Adler & Adler. Cashin resigned from the Roxy to design film costumes for Twentieth Century-Fox (1942-1949). During her tenure at the studio, Cashin designed costumes for more than sixty films including Laura (1944), Anna and the King of Siam (1946), and A tree grows in Brooklyn (1946). From 1949 to 1985 she designed ready-to-wear clothing and accessories, gaining fame as one of the most innovative American designers and a pioneer of twentieth-century sportswear. In her designs and writings, Cashin championed creative independence and efficient use of technology within the fashion industry. Cashin returned to ready-to-wear design for Adler & Adler (1949-1951) before beginning her long association with manufacturer Philip Sills of Sills and Co. in 1953, which lasted until 1977. In 1961, Cashin accepted the offer to launch the Coach handbag company, for whom she designed accessories until 1974. Her designs for that firm remain in production under the title of "Legacy". Cashin followed her Coach years by designing handbags for Meyers (1975-1979). Cashin also designed cashmere separates for Ballantyne of Peebles (1964-1968) as well as for her own company, The Knittery (1970-1980). After the termination of her partnership with Sills and Co., Cashin designed ready-to-wear for manufacturer Russell Taylor (1978-1985) under the labels "Cashin Country" and "Weatherwear". Partnerships with other manufacturers included glove, fur coat, rainwear, loungewear, tote bag, and umbrella designs. Cashin did not employ any design assistants nor did she license her name. Among many industry awards, she received the Coty award five times, and entered their Hall of Fame in 1972. By 1980, Cashin had established the Innovative Design Fund, a non-profit organization to provide funding for design prototypes. She enjoyed a long-standing relationship with the California Institute of Technology, establishing the James Michelin Lecture Series in 1978 as well as the Bonnie Cashin Most Creative Application Essay Award. Cashin died from complications during heart surgery on February 3, 2000 in New York, New York.
Scope and Content
The collection contains Cashin's personal archive documenting her design career. The collection includes Cashin's design illustrations, writings on design, contractual paperwork, photographs of her clothing designs, and press materials including press releases and editorial coverage of her work. Personal photographs and letters to Cashin are also included. Examples of Cashin's fashion and accessory designs in the library's collection are not from the Cashin estate, but were given to the library anonymously in 2005.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Early design work and related documents
Chorus girl costumes
Early ready-to-wear designs
Hollywood film costume and fashion designs
Return to ready-to-wear
Sills and Co. ready-to-wear
Writings and musings by Bonnie Cashin
Fur coat designs
Loungewear designs
Accessory designs
Alex Gropper: Gropper leather wear
Russell Taylor ready-to-wear
Designs for events / Non-commercial collections
Professional photographs of Bonnie Cashin
Personal photographs
Bonnie Cashin notebooks
Personal papers
Rainwear designs
Ford Foundation trip to India
Journalistic coverage of Bonnie Cashin
Publicity materials and citations
Cashin Men ready-to-wear
Knitwear designs
Non-fashion illustrations / Art by Bonnie Cashin
Legal documents and related papers.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Bonnie Cashin Collection of Fashion, Theater and Film Costume Design (7003 items).
Costume.; Women costume designers -- United States -- Archives.; Women fashion designers -- United States -- Archives.; Cashin, Bonnie--Archives.
- Early Design Work and Related Documents, 1920s - 1930s; 7 oversize boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains fashion and costume drawings by Bonnie Cashin spanning her childhood years, adolescence, and early adult design work. The drawings in this series have been subdivided into two subseries for personal or professional use, and are particularly rich in Cashin's costume design illustrations for chorus girls on both Los Angeles and New York stages. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Hollywood High School, 1923 - ca. 1925; 5 oversize boxes (24 folders)
    This subseries contains design illustrations and other artwork created by Bonnie Cashin during her enrollment at Hollywood High School. The subseries primarily consists of costume and fashion design illustrations as well as Cashin's graphic design work for her high school yearbook and local newspapers. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Sketches of Cashin by classmates., ca. 1925; 10 sketches (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Notes and yearbook pages from Cashin's enrollment at Hollywood High School., ca. 1925; 17 pages (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's sketches of cell division for science class., ca. 1925; 2 sketches (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and proofs featuring Cashin's drawings for publication in "General Store Manager" and "Tee Tattler.", ca. 1925; 22 pages (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and proofs featuring Cashin's drawings for publication in fashion column "Modes of the Moment.", ca. 1925; 20 pages (Box 2, Folder 4)
      Includes 2 proofs of sketches and 1 original drawing.
    - Cashin's fashion design illustrations and a self-portrait., ca. 1925; 3 illustrations (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 9 illustrations (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Costume design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 27 illustrations (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Hairstyle survey and fashion silhouettes by Cashin., ca. 1925; 4 illustrations (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Cashin's drawings for Hollywood High School art class., ca. 1925; 28 drawings (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Rough fashion design illustrations in pencil by Cashin., ca. 1925; 19 illustrations (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Pen and ink fashion design illustrations by Cashin., February - October, 1923; 39 illustrations (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 27 illustrations (Box 3, Folder 4)
      General note
      Arranged by "geometric" signature style.
    - Fashion and costume design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 21 illustrations (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Arranged by "flourish" accompanying signature.
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 7 illustrations (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cashin illustrations in the style of "Vogue" magazine covers., ca. 1925; 4 illustrations (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Cashin illustrations in the style of contemporary fashion magazines., ca. 1925; 3 illustrations (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Cashin illustrations in the style of fashion magazine covers / fashion patterns., ca. 1925; 5 illustrations (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Cartoonish drawings, with humorous captions, by Cashin., ca. 1925; 3 illustrations (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Figure studies by Cashin., ca. 1925; 5 drawings (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Cashin illustrations in the style of "Vogue Patterns.", ca. 1925; 5 illustrations (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Fashion design illustrations in pencil by Cashin., ca. 1925; 16 illustrations (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 8 illustrations (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925; 16 illustrations (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Early Professional Work, ca. 1925 - 1930; 2 oversize boxes
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's first professional fashion design illustrations. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations for "Caroline's Gowns" logo design., ca. 1925 - 1930; 6 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 9 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 28 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's illustrations of stage sets., ca. 1925 - 1930; 2 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fashion design illustrations, with narrative captions, by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 5 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Fashion design illustrations in pencil by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 30 illustrations (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Cashin's high school musings and paperwork., ca. 1925; 5 pages (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Cartoonish drawings, with humorous captions, by Cashin., ca. 1925; 27 items (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Illustrations, with notes for publication, by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 23 illustrations (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 23 illustrations (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 30 illustrations (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1925 - 1930; 30 illustrations (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Chorus Girl Costumes, 1930s; 2 oversize boxes
  This series contains costume design illustrations and publicity photographs of costume designs by Bonnie Cashin. All illustrations contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Fanchon and Marco Dance Troupe / Roxy Theatre, 1930s; 1 oversize box and 2 folders
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's costume design illustrations and photographs of chorus girls wearing her costume designs. All illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Chorus girl costume design illustrations by Cashin for Fanchon and Marco; Folder 1 of 2., ca. 1925 - 1930; 35 illustrations (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chorus girl costume design illustrations by Cashin for Fanchon and Marco; Folder 2 of 2., ca. 1925 - 1930; 35 illustrations (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of single performers or partial chorus line wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 15 photographs (Box 9, Folder 1)
      No photographer noted. Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of complete chorus line wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 17 photographs (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 13 photographs (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Photographers noted: Archer's Studio, Hollywood (8 items), Irving Archer, Hollywood (4 items). Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 7 photographs (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Photographer noted: Curt Fox, L.A. (6 items), Curt Fox, Los Angeles (1 item). Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 12 photographs (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Photographer noted: J. A. Partington, Jr. Note all shots are of full chorus and stage details. Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 8 photographs (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Photographer noted: Harry Wenger, L.A. See also Box 9, folder 8. Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 5 photographs (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Photographers noted: C. W. F. (1 item), Paralta, L.A. (2 items), Maurice Seymour (2 items). Some include original press releases regarding production.
    - Photographs of chorus girls wearing costumes designed by Cashin., 1930s; 15 photographs (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Photographer noted: Harry Wenger, L.A. (8 items.) Some include original press releases regarding production. See also Box 9, folder 6.
- Early Ready-to-Wear Designs, 1938 - 1943; 3 folders
  This series contains fashion design illustrations by Bonnie Cashin. The series includes related publicity and is subdivided into two subseries for her uniform designs during world War II and her ready-to-wear fashion designs for manufacturer Adler and Adler. All illustrations contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Adler and Adler: First Contract Period, ca. 1940 - 1943; 2 folders
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's fashion design illustrations and photographs of models wearing her designs. All illustrations by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's ready-to-wear fashion design illustrations for Adler and Adler., ca. 1940; 7 illustrations (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Published photographs of Cashin ready-to-wear designs for Adler and Adler., ca. 1940 - 1943; 2 photographs (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Designs for World War II Civilian Uniforms, ca. 1940 - December 1941; 1 folder
    This subseries contains editorial documentation of Bonnie Cashin's designs for women's civilian defense uniforms for use during World War II.
    - Documents regarding Cashin's designs for World War II uniforms., ca. 1940 - December 1941; 5 pages (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Hollywood Film Costume and Fashion Designs, 1943 - 1949; 6 oversize boxes
  This series contains film costume and fashion design illustrations by Bonnie Cashin as well as Cashin's writings on designing in Hollywood and related publicity. The series is subdivided into two subseries for costume design illustrations for Twentieth Century-Fox and fashion design illustrations for private clients, as well as one unproduced screenplay co-authored by Cashin. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Unproduced Screenplay, ca. 1945; 1 folder
    This subseries consists of one unproduced screenplay co-authored by Bonnie Cashin. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Screenplay "Leave It to Homer" written by Cashin and Robert White., ca. 1945; 1 volume (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Off-Screen Fashion Designs, 1943 - 1949; 2 oversize boxes and 4 folders
    This subseries contains fashion design illustrations and related memos on fashion design by Bonnie Cashin. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Writings by Cashin regarding film costume and fashion design., 1945 - 1949; 50 pages (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Photographs and editorial clippings of actresses wearing Cashin's fashion designs., 1943 - 1949; 28 pages (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Some images published in "Redbook" magazine (August 1948), clipping included.
    - Negatives of actresses wearing Cashin's fashion designs., 1943 - 1949; 32 negatives (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Drawings by Cashin., 1943 - 1949; 5 drawings (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's design illustrations for hats and head covers., 1943 - 1949; 3 illustrations (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's essay titled "Close-ups.", 1943 - 1949; 1 page (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's essays and fashion design illustrations titled "Bras Bravos.", 1946 - 1949; 6 pages (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Cashin's essay and fashion design illustrations titled "Heading for Gold.", 1943 - 1949; 11 pages (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Essay and fashion design illustrations by Cashin., 1943 - 1949; 3 pages (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Fashion design illustrations of togas and ponchos by Cashin., 1943 - 1949; 6 illustrations (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., 1943 - 1949; 15 illustrations (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., 1943 - 1949; 32 illustrations (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Fashion design illustrations of togas and use of scarves for dresses by Cashin., ca. 1945; 4 illustrations (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., ca. 1944 - 1947; 12 illustrations (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Cashin's fashion design illustrations of "Goddess"-inspired dresses., ca. 1946; 3 illustrations (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin., 1947 - 1949; 12 illustrations (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Articles regarding and photographs of actresses in Cashin's film costume and fashion designs., 1944 - April 20, 1946; 4 pages (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Sketches by Cashin while traveling in Europe., 1948-1949; 13 sketches (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Fashion design illustrations by Cashin, some with swatches., 1940s; 16 illustrations (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Twentieth Century-Fox: Film Costumes, 1943 - 1949; 4 folders
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin film costume design illustrations, film stills and editorial coverage featuring Cashin's costume designs. All illustrations and writings by Bonnie Cashin contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's costume design illustrations for "Anna and the King of Siam.", 1946; 3 illustrations (Box 14, Folder 1)
      very fragile
    - Articles and memos written by and regarding Cashin at work in Hollywood., 1943 - 1949; 9 pages (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Film stills of Cashin costume designs for Twentieth Century-Fox., 1944 - 1946; 4 photographs (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations for "dream sequence" in Betty Grable feature film., 1947; 2 illustrations (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Return to Ready-to-Wear, 1949 - 1954; 5 oversize boxes
  This series contains Bonnie Cashin's fashion designs illustrations and publicity photographs of designs by Cashin. The series is particularly rich in designs for manufacturer Adler and Adler. The series has been subdivided into six subseries for evening wear designs, photographs, reduced sketches, original sketches, one sketchbook, and designs for manufacturer Leonard L. Levy. All materials contained in this series are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
  - Adler and Adler: First Evening Wear Collection, Fall 1949; 1 folder
    This subseries consists of photographs of Bonnie Cashin's first evening wear collection for manufacturer Adler and Adler. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Black and white photographs of Cashin's evening wear designs for Adler and Adler., Fall 1949; 2 photographs (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Adler and Adler: Reduced Sketches of Coat, Suit and Dress Designs, 1949 - 1951; 3 folders
    This subseries contains reduced photocopied or photostatic reproductions of Bonnie Cashin's ready-to-wear design illustrations for manufacturer Adler and Adler. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's illustrations and blurbs regarding togas designed for Adler and Adler; see also box 19, folders 2 - 11., 1950; 8 illustrations (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs, with style numbers, for Adler and Adler's Resort and Spring line., 1949 - 1950; 31 illustrations (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Cashin's illustrations of ready-to-wear designs for Adler and Adler., 1950 - 1951; 20 illustrations (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Adler and Adler; Sketchbook, 1949; 1 volume
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's sketchbook of ready-to-wear designs for manufacturer Adler and Adler. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.
    - Cashin's sketchbook of designs for Adler and Adler., 1949; 1 volume (Box 158, Folder 1)
  - Sketches (Return to Ready-to-Wear), 1950 - Ca. 1953; 1 oversize box
    This subseries contains Bonnie Cashin's illustrations of garment designs for unknown manufacturers. All materials contained in this subseries are protected by United States copyright law and may not be reproduced, distributed, transmitted, displayed, published or broadcast without the prior written permission of The Bonnie Cashin Foundation.